artificial intelligence updates every
week on Friday at 2 p.m. Eastern. Today,
Friday, May 8th, and as you can see, a
lot of updates. And uh the slogan for
today is that this year, your agents
have agents. And let's look at our
leaderboard arena. And uh it looks
basically the same. Claude again is the
leader. I'm very curious about Muse
Spark. I haven't used it myself and uh
it's not open source. It's coming from
meta but it's not open source and they
didn't disclose the size of it but uh
based on the speed people speculate that
it's small that it may be as small as 30
billion parameters. I don't know most of
these models are huge. The ballpark is
usually about trillion parameters. So
yeah. Uh next uh uh deepseek uh well CLI
or terminal uh user interface. Yeah,
this is very interesting project. It
started in January and recently it was
just exploding. So what it is it's a
open-source uh framework uh to run
deepseeek. Uh it is a kind of harness uh
which you can use it is written in rust.
So and you can use it on any platform uh
whether it is uh Windows or Mac or Linux
and uh they uh show that it's actually
better if if you're using DeepS then
DeepS TUI is the way to go. You can of
course use DeepSseek with open code and
clot code and other harnesses but this
is like specifically tuned to work with
deepseek and if you do that then your
costs go down dramatically. So these are
all uh the websites uh there's a GitHub
and uh next uh Antropic uh Wall Street
uh partnership 1.5 billion uh was just
uh announced. It's a joint venture. So
it looks like Antropic becoming the def
facto technology uh for for Wall Street.
Uh Antropic Space X compute deal. So the
deal is uh big because they they're
taking over the SpaceX's Colossus 1 data
center in Memphis which is a huge data
center. But on the other side, if you
look at the total compute which uh
Antropic uses, so most of it uh 57% come
from Amazon, 40% from Google and this
SpaceX deal is only 3%. And Microsoft
and others are very very small. Oh,
Antropic plus SpaceX computers in low
earth orbit. Cloud computing is now
technically accurate. Okay, this is just
a joke. um entropic cloud security in
public beta for cloud enterprise. So
it's AI powered security tool directly
into cloud AI uses latest model
multi-stage validation process and so
on. So this is entropic announcement. Uh
next uh new and cloud managed agents
dreaming outcomes and multi- aent
orchestration.
Uh so dreaming uh means that it
periodically reviews past sessions and
kind of compresses and uh this you can
talk about it as infinite context
windows. Um so it learns from experience
and dreaming is used to compact and
restructure the knowledge outcomes goal
plus uh specs graded loop and uh
acceptable outcome. So you tell it what
to achieve and it uh goes towards this
goal. Uh multi- aent orchestration uh
spawns additional sessions at runtime.
Okay. Uh
this is a plug to my channel as usual.
We have 7.7 uh,000 subscribers, 285
videos. Uh channel name my name left
selector. download slides from GitHub
and uh from Google Drive. I provide
links under the video and I always ask a
question. So please pause the video,
find the question and answer it. Uh XAI
Gro connectors.
So now uh if you are using um uh gro I I
think this is only for paid and u even
more for like more um corporate uh users
uh aimed for nontechnical users no
config so you im immediately can start
working with uh uh Google workspace
Gmail drive and and so on and can do
regular operations
Uh well if you compare it with open claw
or hermas or claw desktop they provide
more flexibility but uh they also
usually need more technical knowledge.
Uh open swarm AI this is interesting
GitHub project uh if if by the way if
you search for open swarm there are so
many projects and companies. So this
particular one is uh to generate slide
decks, reports and videos from prompt
and it is a uh orchestrator agent which
coordinates its specialized agents for
research, data analysis, document
formatting, video generation,
everything. Um so I guess this is a very
good project. Uh next, oh I just wanted
to make this image and I went through
several iterations. So if I am now
talking to LLM
all right so this is me on the left and
this is LLM on the right in fact I go
through stages of harnesses so for
example I'm using a clot code which is a
harness which can create uh which uses
its own agentic loop which analyzes my
question which can use u local tools uh
and then it passes uh whatever if if it
wants to communicate with the LLM in the
cloud it um passes it sends the message
but this message hits not the LLM
directly it s hits the remote harness
the remote agent which has the same
agentic loop well not the same because
it's using uh other tools it's like
searching web uh code execution in cloud
virtual environment and and so on but
this is just just to understand so now
you have a chain of harnesses
uh next perplexity workflows. Uh this is
a feature within Perplexity computer. Uh
the Perplexity pushes I receive emails
offering me to start using a computer.
Uh so yeah, this is uh just one more
feature. I I think it's a good thing,
but you have to pay for it. Uh
miscellaneous AI news. Um I really like
this channel and there's some random
news like for example Nvidia Numatron 3
Nano Omni Open Weight Vision Audio and
so on. Pullside AI has models, small
models and bigger models. Alibaba image
2.0 pro ranked pretty high. XAI think
fast low latency voice model. Oh, China
blocked acquisition of Manus uh for Meta
and Meta already invested heavily in
integrating Manus in their
infrastructure. So now they have to yank
it out. Um, Gemini can now generate and
export PDFs, docs, and Excel files. Uh,
Google Translate, uh, pronunciation
practice 11 Labs music. Uh, Spotify
added green check marks for real human
artists to separate them from AI. May
your clinic, oh, this this is good. Uh,
developed an AI model that can detect
pancreatic cancer in scans 3 years
before clinical diagnosis is typically
possible. So this is early diagnostics
of pancreatic cancer which of course is
uh has no cure. So this is great uh open
claw updates. Well as usual almost every
day May 1st, second, third like you have
a lot of updates. This is good but this
is also making it difficult to work with
open claw because it always changing and
sometimes these changes are disruptive
or they're buggy.
And this uh video he actually explains
uh you see open claw despite offering
powerful capabilities
uh constantly breaks with updates
creating daily frustrations for users.
So he uh created his own system we also
creating our own systems and many people
do that. Uh Hermas agent creator uh
instead of user speaking agents creator
automatically selects the best agent for
each job and runs them in sequence. So
this is a good uh project. Uh no AI
agent orchestration needed. This is a
very very interesting paper. Uh
remember like two years ago when the
models were primitive and stupid and
couldn't handle a lot of data. what you
would do, you would use multiple agents
and you will try to orchestrate them to
make them work together and it was very
very difficult and painful. But today
because models are much smarter and can
handle longer context, you can take a
complicated uh task like here for
example this is a diagram of something
which the system needs to do and you can
just give it as one task to let's say
claude 4.5 and it can handle it and they
found that it is easier uh just to give
it to one model than to try to split it
and do something like crewi or lang
graph um with those systems multi- aent
frameworks it makes it more difficult
and the results are worse so frontier
models have become sophisticated enough
to handle complex procedures
holistically without external
scaffolding which can fragment reasoning
introduce failure modes okay oh this is
by the way uh here I spoke about the
Hermas agent ketta so this is about
Hermas agent it recently had two
updates. One is self-maintaining skill
management. So it maintains its skills
and another it finishes what it starts.
It's called tenacity release. So just
yesterday anyway um
uh hardness more important than the
model. Again this is papers in archive
and what they show is that by changing
the hardness you can achieve six times
performance change. So if something
doesn't work, you see the critical
insight is substraction principle. As
models improve, successful harness
engineering involves removing
unnecessary components. When agents
underperform, audit the harness first
rather than switching the models. So
harness inforge a back end for AI coding
agents. uh what it is it's uh kind of a
database uh which uh the system can use
and uh because of that uh so you can use
caching and uh you use less tokens and
uh cost goes down. So here's for example
if you're using superbase or if you're
using ins forge uh it's a dramatic
decrease in cost as you can see. Uh next
uh Google demined uh AI co- clinician.
So they uh created this uh model which
helps uh doctors in many like patient
history collection, diagnostic
reasoning, examination guidance. Uh yeah
and looks like the quality becomes
better. uh trading agents open source
multi- aent LLM framework that simulates
a Wall Street trading firm
has specialized agents covering
fundamentals u uh sentiment news
technical analysis debating willbe
researchers and so on project surpassed
53,000 GitHub stars okay so who needs uh
financial firms when you can use open
project on GitHub which will work as a
trading firm Anyway, uh next uh
superpowers agentic framework. Yes, this
is a very interesting project. Uh Jesse
Vincent is the author and u it is uh
several composable skills for tools like
cloth code and codex enforcing rigorous
standards and so on. So it's agentic
framework and software development
methodology designed to transition AI
coding from VIP coding to professional
engineering. Right? So it's a testdriven
development, sub agent orchestrations.
Additionally, offers experimental
features like interactive control. Is
like a terminal. So you can have
multiple terminal sessions inside one
session. So uh interactive control and
headless Windows uh VMs. Okay. Uh looks
looks like a good project. Uh Andre
Carpath talk at squ event.
Well, I will not go through the whole
thing. It's usually uh interesting to
watch. There is a video where Mad Burman
comments on the the whole presentation.
Um he describes kind of the history of
AI software was explicit human then uh
programming by arranging data sets for
neural network and now treat LLM as a
new computing platform. VIP coding
verifiability
jaggedness why uh model is very smart in
some areas and very stupid in others
right uh the bitter lesson human
heristic rules lose uh to end to end
neural networks trained on data yeah
this is a famous like for example Google
translate there were half a million
lines of code which eventually uh lost
to stupid network which was just trained
on data
Uh this is the beta lesson. Uh Tesla
transition from human coded driving
rules to neural network approach.
Agentic engineering versus uh vibe
coding. So vibe coding raises the floor
and agentic engineering raises the
ceiling enabling professional engineers
to orchestrate swarms of agent to
maintain high quality and massive
productivity. Um I am myself going
through this evolution going from um AI
helping me a little bit to AI actually
doing all heavy lifting and running for
a long time doing a lot of updates uh
planning and uh verifying testing.
Karpath suggests that while we can
outsource thinking to AI we cannot
outsource understanding or taste. Okay.
And internet needs to be rebuilt for
agents.
uh Boris Churnney why coding is solved.
Well, he become a true celebrity because
he's the guy who originally created Clot
Code and uh yeah, so he in this talk um
accidentally created Clot Code in late
which is what uh a year something ago,
right? Clot code gained exponential
growth uh starting with Oppus 4 in the
middle of last year and he now writes
100% of his code using AI agents
managing hundreds of concurrent agents
from his phone and using automated loops
that continuously maintain his code base
fix issues and process feedback. So he
predicts coding will become a
democratized as literacy after the
printing press enabling anyone to build
software regardless of the technical
background. So he coined the press that
this is a printing press moment
historical moment. Uh yeah how cloud
code works. This is a very interesting
video. So what the creator of this video
does, he reproduces the clo code
functionality and he explains the
building the pieces of the cloth uh code
harness and how you do something
similar. So key components repository
mapping identifies entry points core
tools like file operations run bash
script describe things search tools and
so on. So you can see a list and uh he
actually went through this exercise of
creating harness himself. Uh same model
different harness six times the
performance. Somewhere a project manager
is adding harness engineer to LinkedIn.
Yeah it's it's a new profession. Uh
video and audio Hicksfield AI a lot of
progress huge speed of growth. So this
company uh already uh over 1.3 billion
valuation uh his field allows you to
produce a short uh cinematic AI videos
and images from text prompts using
different models and uh generates 4
million videos per day. Well, I haven't
tried Hicksfield myself, but I tried it
sooner and it's a lot of fun. uh you
subscribe for free and uh then you get
free credits for like 10 songs and when
I say song that means uh you can give it
lyrics but it can also generate it all
own lyrics you just tell it what kind of
song what kind of music what kind of
rhythm what kind of mood whatever and it
just generates the whole thing with
orchestrations and uh let's say you want
to hear something romantic in French
okay you'll get it in in in just a
minute and you can download it and
listen to it uh annualized revenue is
more than 300 million valuation at 5
billion and yeah sooner I highly
recommend to try it's very easy uh
Microsoft copilot actions and co-work so
copilot usually was very simplistic but
now it can do complex agentic work re
real agentic so this this is a big
progress and it is integrated into whole
office so schedule meetings, send
emails, perform tasks using your work
data and so on. Uh Codex uh CLI new goal
feature again agenting thing you just
you show the intent and it uh works
towards achieving this intent. And by
the way, Codex became very good and some
people recommend to use codex uh
together with clo code not either or but
use them together. It's actually
possible and they complimentary uh
Hermes agent goals system again same
thing users yeah I already spoke when I
was talking about updates the swarm
model allows multiple agents to work
simultaneously together towards uh the
goal uh Google remy completes with
competes with open claw okay Google now
also created their own agent it's called
remy it's in the cloud it works with
Google uh workspace is Gmail, docs,
calendar and so on and operates
continuously in the background. Uh I
don't know like all companies provide
their own agents now uh open a GPT55
instant. Uh so if you go in chat GPT in
OpenAI now uh you will see 55 is a
default and uh it has less
hallucinations and people really like
it. Um I actually like it. I used it
today and uh yeah I liked it. uh
hyperframes
uh open source HTML to video yet another
way to generate video but now uh you
know that um AI tools can generate HTML
easily so there are a lot of software
packages AI driven which generate u u
front end for websites whatever so here
it's very interesting so this system can
generate front end using HTML CSS
process in JavaScript and then renders
it into the real video in MP4 files.
Headless Chrome and FFmpeg works with CL
code uh has tools for uh text to speech
transcription and so on. Uh Unity AI. So
now we're talking about gaming uh in
open beta for Unity 6 developers.
Agentic assistance with two modes ask
and agent. Can write C# scripts,
generate assets, textures and so on.
Supports visual models. Uh yeah, this
this is a big big world of gaming. Uh Z
editor. I am now only using Z editor. Uh
my son uh recommended uh and I
downloaded half a year ago, but back
then it was not that good. But now they
officially uh released version 1 1.0
something uh and I tried it again and
I'm absolutely sold on it. So I'm not
using visual visual studio code anymore.
It's done. Uh in fact when I open Finder
window on my Mac I now have a special
button which I programmed and by
clicking it I open Z editor in this
directory so I can work. So what's good
about it? Well, the screen looks like
Visual Studio Code, but it's really
fast. Uh, it supports GPU. It written in
Rust. It is very small in memory. Uh, it
just like absolutely boom and it's open.
Uh, it supports um agents uh like I I
use cloud agent which is uh cloud code
right inside. Everything just works. Uh
the shortcuts is very easy. The
configuration process is very very easy.
It is very helpful.
I I don't know. I I just fell in love
with it. And I I want to tell a little
bit story about it. So nothing sober.
This is this guy in the middle. So he
created an editor called atom in 2011.
Back then he was at GitHub and uh so it
was open- source editor and everything
was good. Uh but then uh GitHub uh uh
was bought by Microsoft and Microsoft
decided that they will build their own
visual studio code. So they killed uh
Atom and eventually retired in 2022. So
what these guys did they said okay let
us create another editor but this time
it will not be in Typescript we will
write it in Rust and we will make it
good and we will add AI support from the
get- go uh so is a startup they received
some money uh what is the number I'm
trying to read here I thought it's like
$30 million oh yeah $32 million in last
year and uh last month they released
version one um these guys are very very
talented you know the uh electron
framework which runs visual studio code
they actually invented it when they were
building their atom editor so any anyway
uh it is elegant it is high performance
it's like it's really really good I
highly recommend very easy to install
well you will spend some time maybe a
day or two to configure it to your
liking all the colors all the themes all
the position of the windows or whatever
you want. But then I'm sure you just
love it. You can start it from your
finder. You can start it from terminal
like Z space dot or space or Z space
file name. Just very very easy to use.
Jujitsu version control. Uh yes uh this
is uh maybe I shouldn't include it here
but for people who use uh uh git
uh this is a very way uh very good way
to make your life easier right uh so
it's a version uh control system people
from outside they will not even know
that you are using it it's just u you
use your own commands they all start
with JJ and they make multiple snapshots
and they uh do rebasing automatically so
you don't have to think about it. It
just makes your life easier. Uh merging
you know that standard git uh when it
compares file it files it does it line
by line which is very stupid. Uh but
there are better ways mergraph and weave
especially weave. So it goes further
with entity level merging. understands
functions, classes, and methods in
discrete units and it figures out like
even if you move them in the file or
whatever, it figures out what have
changed. Um, yeah. So, it's not AI yet,
but it's much better than a regular
merge. And, uh, Jack Dorsey
uh, lays off 4,000 workers of his
company, which is about 40% of his work.
So this is Jack Dorsey and this is a
video Julie McCoy she talks about it
that a lot of uh technical layoffs uh in
uh this year directly attributed to AI.
So and she talks well how to adapt and
survive audit operations for AI
integration sheet from doing task to
orchestrating AI agents and capitalize
on the lowered cost of building new
businesses. Okay. uh Mo Goddat uh he's a
former uh Google uh executive again very
good video where he talks how to survive
and again key survival skills master AI
as a tool develop extreme agility for
rapid pivoting maintain strong ethics in
AI development and critically question
information to avoid manipulation so
what he is saying that business is
changing from something long-term to
something which needs to pivot every
like on the spot very fast. Oh, here
shift from long-term strategic planning
to daily reactive agility. So, this is
the key idea. Okay, these are the
layoffs. Uh this month, the biggest
PayPal. Uh so, they uh laid off almost
5,000 people, which is about 20% of the
company.
Okay. And this is me as usual. And thank
you